If you rip open the new World Cup ball,
you'd find this sensor hidden inside.
It's collecting data 500 times a second.
The sensor used to be hung on a
suspension system like this, so it
wouldn't feel any different to the
players, but it was also more fragile
every time it got
So, this new sensor only weighs about 14
g or a couple sheets of paper, but they
still needed to balance it out. So, they
added counterweights across the other
three panels. During games, the sensor
tells you where the ball is on the field
and if it's been touched by a player.
Even a little bit results in signals
like this and a bounce or a kick looks
like this. So, this high-tech ball helps
track things like offsides or out of
bounds or if the ball has crossed the
goal line. But, if you want to see
sports tech that got banned for being
too good, subscribe.